* _Last updated: July 1, 2025_
    
    Forbes Media LLC (“**Forbes**”, “**Company**”, “**we**”, “**our**”, or “**us**”) understands that privacy is important to our users. This Privacy Statement describes our practices regarding the collection, use, sharing, and protection of your personal information in connection the services, products, features, and offerings we provide to you (the “**Services**”), including without limitation our print magazine subscriptions, and our digital Services like Forbes.com, Forbes mobile applications, and Forbes games (collectively, the “**Site**”), and our Forbes newsletters, podcasts, and other digital sites, communications, and media (collectively with the Site, the “**Properties**”). This Privacy Statement also tells you about the rights and choices you have with respect to your personal information, how you can assert those rights, and how you can contact us to get answers to your questions.
    
    With respect to the personal information that our clients and their vendors collect from you outside of our Properties and/or Services (“**Service Data**”), where permitted by law, we generally process such information only as a “service provider” or “data processor” (as those terms are defined under applicable data protection laws) on behalf of our clients, who act as the “business” or “data controller” (as those terms are defined under applicable data protection laws). Our clients—for example, companies that use our lead generation services—are the parties that control the use of the Service Data and determine the purposes for which we process such information. While this Privacy Statement describes how we process Service Data on behalf of our clients, our clients are responsible for their own practices in collecting, using, and disclosing information they collect from you. To learn more about such clients’ use of your information and your rights that you may have over such information, please consult the privacy policy of the applicable company or publisher.
    
    Please note that our privacy practices are subject to the applicable laws of the regions in which we operate. Accordingly, some additional region-specific terms will only apply to individuals in those locations, or as required by applicable laws.
    
    For more information about how users with disabilities can access this Privacy Statement in an alternative format, please contact [privacy@forbes.com](mailto:privacy@forbes.com) or 866-536-7262.
    
    BY USING OR ACCESSING THE PROPERTIES OR OUR SERVICES, YOU AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH OUR POLICIES OR PRACTICES, YOU SHOULD NOT USE OR ACCESS THE PROPERTIES OR SERVICES OR PROVIDE US WITH ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION.
    
    **Quick Links**

    [**Colorado, Connecticut, Delaware, Iowa, Minnesota, Montana, Nebraska, New Hampshire, New Jersey, Oregon, Tennessee, Texas, Utah, Virginia and Similar U.S. State Privacy Rights**](#state-privacy-rights)

    #### WHAT OUR PRIVACY STATEMENT COVERS
    
    This Privacy Statement applies only to user information collected or created by us or shared with us in relation to our Properties or Services. While you may encounter links on the Properties to other websites, such as those relating to our third-party sponsors, advertisers, and other partners (e.g., our affiliate network operators), including when you sign into Forbes.com using a social media or digital wallet service, please note that these websites are not covered by this Privacy Statement (unless otherwise noted on such site, which may be the case if, for example, the site is also owned and operated by Forbes).
    
    We may provide different or additional privacy notices in connection with certain activities, programs, and offerings (for example, if you submit a job application through the Properties). Additionally, we may provide additional “just-in-time” notices or notices at collection that may supplement or clarify our privacy practices or provide you with additional choices regarding your personal information.
    
    This Privacy Statement does not apply to the activities of Forbes’ third-party sponsors, advertisers, and other partners (e.g., our affiliate network operators) that may collect your personal information while you access or use such third party’s services in connection with your use of our Properties (e.g., social media and sharing services, digital wallet logins, widgets, inline frames containing games (like Pinpoint by LinkedIn), and/or interactive mini-programs that run on the Properties). This Privacy Statement also does not apply to Forbes’ third-party licensees, who manage and run their own Forbes-branded services and sites, some of whom the Properties link out to. The privacy and information practices of those third parties are not covered by this Privacy Statement. To learn more about the policies of such third parties, we encourage you to read and review the privacy statements of each third-party service that you may choose to use.
    
    We offer widgets that are hosted on the Properties, such as our embeddable video player. Use of the Forbes.com widgets is subject to our Site’s [Terms of Use](https://www.forbes.com/terms-and-conditions), but downloading or embedding these widgets on other websites is not covered by this Privacy Statement.
    
    #### **PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT FROM YOU**
    
    We use the term “personal information” – also called “personal data” or “personally identifiable information” in the laws of some jurisdictions – to refer to information that reasonably identifies, relates to, describes, or can be associated with you. The following are categories and types of personal information that we may collect from or about you, depending on how you interact with the Properties and our Services:
    
    * Identifiers, such as your name and email address;
        
    * Contact information, such as your mailing address and telephone number;
        
    * Payment information, such as credit or debit card information;
        
    * Transaction or Commercial information, such as your purchase or investment preferences and your subscriptions and purchases with us or with your digital wallet address;
        
    * Profile information, such as photos, videos, or other information about you and your interests posted or included in connection with a user profile;
        
    * Job and employment information, such as the name of your company, industry, and job title;
        
    * Education information, such as school attended and degree obtained;
        
    * Preferences, such as marketing and privacy preferences and choice of subscription;
        
    * Device and online identifiers and related information, including internet protocol (IP) address, mobile ad identifiers, data collected from cookies, beacons, and pixel tags, and similar unique identifiers;
        
    * Internet or other electronic network activity information, including, but not limited to browsing history, search history, Forbes game statistics (like your score, time played, winning streak, and ranking compared to other players), and information regarding your interaction with an internet website, application, email, mobile app, or advertisement;
        
    * Geolocation or other information that permits us to determine your location;
        
    * Demographic information, such as your age or gender;
        
    * Inferences we may create about you;
        
    * Any other personal information that you or somebody on your behalf voluntarily provide us.

    If you interact with us on social media or use features such as plugins, widgets, or other tools made available by social media platforms or networks in connection with our Properties, or if you choose to sign up for a paid subscription via your social media profile, we may collect information that you share with us on social media or that such platforms share with us. Please review the privacy policies and settings of the social media platforms and networks that you use for more information about their privacy practices. For additional information, see the section titled **Third-Party Sources** below.
    
    If you choose to log into one of our Properties using a digital wallet, we may collect public data points such as your wallet address, the blockchain your wallet is on, your wallet’s transactions and transaction history, and whether your wallet holds a Forbes digital collectable.
    
    Where you sign-up for paid subscriptions as a gift option (e.g., on behalf of a friend or colleague, the gift recipient), you may provide us with personal information on behalf of the gift recipient.
    
    #### HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
    
    ****Personal Information You Provide****
    
    We collect personal information that you provide to us directly. This may include, but is not limited to, information you provide:
    
    * When you contact us via phone, email or text message, or through other Internet-enabled communications;
        
    * When you subscribe to one of our print or digital Services;
        
    * When you register to become a member of the Site or create a user profile;
        
    * When you register for one of our live or virtual events;
        
    * On your member profile page and public profile URL (for example, if you choose to add content to your profile page, such as photos, videos or other information about you and your interests);
        
    * To enter into a sweepstakes, contest, or promotion, or to apply for consideration in connection with a Forbes list or similar accolade (e.g., Under 30 list applications);
        
    * When you order something from the Properties or one of our co-branded websites;
        
    * When you post content to the Properties;
        
    * In your response to surveys that you choose to complete for us;
        
    * If you log into one of our Properties with your digital wallet;
        
    * When you make search queries or play games on the Properties; and
        
    * When you otherwise voluntarily provide us with personal information on or through the Properties or Services.

    You always have the option not to provide the information we request. If you choose not to provide the information we request, you can still access and use portions of the Properties, but you may be unable to access certain options and services, such as paid subscription content. If you wish to provide user information to us about a third party, such your friend or colleague, in connection with a referral, gift subscription, corporate subscription, recommendation, nomination (e.g., Under 30 list nomination), or other purpose, please only do so if you have the permission of that third party. When you register or become a member of the Site or provide information to Forbes in any other manner, you agree to provide only true, accurate, current and complete information.
    
    ****Personal Information We Collect Automatically****
    
    When you visit our Properties, open or click on emails we send you, or interact with our advertisements or games, we or third parties we work with may automatically collect certain information using technologies such as cookies and other tracking technologies described below.
    
    ****Cookies and Similar Technology****
    
    “Cookies” are pieces of information that may be placed on your device by a website for the purpose of collecting data to facilitate and enhance your communication and interaction with that website. Such data may include, for example, the address of the websites you visited before and after you visited our Properties, the type of browser you are using, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, what pages in the Properties you visited and what links you clicked on, the region where your device is located, and geographic information based on your IP data. We may store some information on your device or device hard drive as a cookie or similar type of file (such as clear gifs, pixels, web beacons, tags, and similar technologies that work on mobile devices) to collect data related to usage of the Properties. We may also use cookies to customize your visit to the Properties (including our emails), to serve advertisements, and for other purposes to make your visit more convenient or to enable us to enhance the Properties.
    
    Cookies fall into the subcategories below:
    
    * **Required (sometimes referred to as “Essential”).** Certain cookies are used for specific purposes that are essential to your secure use and navigation of the Properties so that we are able to provide you with the services you request. Without them, Forbes may not be able to provide core Property functions and features to you, and the Property would not operate as well as you or Forbes would like. For example, they enable core functions like carrying out network transmissions and enabling you to log in to our systems. They also enable us to comply with legal obligations in regions with laws that apply to cookies, like by maintaining your cookie consent choices in regions that require consent or, in opt-out regions, by preventing advertising-related or other optional digital trackers from being placed on your browser or device if you have opted out. These cookies collect and use information such as your server preferences, single-session data and corresponding identifier, web beacons and log files (detailed below), and other credential-related information. Required cookies cannot be switched off on our Properties.
        
    * **Functional.** Other cookies may be used to collect and process information about your preferences and similar choices in connection with the Properties in order to allow us to provide enhanced functionality, customization and personalization, such as by remembering your login information or other choices or by providing you with more personalized features (e.g., various local preference settings; which geographically-customized version of the Properties and related content you may prefer). Functional cookies include social media cookies, which collect information about your social media usage and other data you may have provided in connection with such usage (if you access the Site through a social media website or mobile application, you may have social media cookies). If you wish to modify or change your social media cookies, please visit and review the settings on your applicable social media account(s).
        
    * **Analytics.** These cookies allow us to better understand our users’ actions and interests, for instance, by tracking clicks, visits, and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our Properties and services. This allows us to provide a high-quality experience by customizing our offerings and quickly identifying and fixing any issues that arise. For example, we might use analytics cookies to keep track of which pages are most popular, which method of linking between pages is most effective, and to determine why some pages are receiving error messages.
        
    * **Advertising.** To help support the Properties and further tailor your experience, Forbes and its advertising partners (and/or their third-party analytics providers) may also use cookies on the Properties (including in emails) to personalize the content and advertisements you may be shown. Such advertisements use cookies to provide you targeted advertisements that may be more consistent with your interests than non-targeted advertisements. Certain Forbes advertising partners may also use cookies to monitor or track the performance of their advertising content, including native advertising content (e.g., BrandVoice), including how you interact with the advertising content, even in situations where the ad is displayed on another site. If you do not allow these trackers on our Properties, you may still receive advertisements, but you may receive less relevant advertising or content.

    In certain countries and U.S. states, you can opt out or set preferences regarding cookies using our cookie management tool when a device you utilize visits our Properties. You may also be able to set preferences related to certain interest-based advertisements and targeted ads by using tools provided by self-regulatory programs like the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) program at [www.aboutads.info/consumers>](https://www.forbes.com/privacy/english/www.aboutads.info/consumers) and the Network Advertising Initiative at [http://optout.networkadvertising.org/](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). To learn how, please see the **Your Choices** section below.
    
    The Properties’ web and ad servers log information about a user's IP address, browser type, and the current URL the user is requesting. This information is always provided by a user's browser and automatically logged by most websites. These log files are stored in a secure location and used for internal business purposes such as internal analysis of traffic patterns within our Properties.
    
    ****Clickstream Data****
    
    As you use the Internet, a trail of electronic information is left at each website you visit. This information, which is sometimes referred to as “clickstream data,” can be collected and stored by a website's server. Clickstream data can tell us the type of computer and browsing software you use and the address of the website from which you linked to the Properties. We may collect and use clickstream data as a form of aggregate information to anonymously determine how much time visitors spend on each page of our Properties, how visitors navigate throughout the Properties, and how we may tailor our web pages to better meet the needs of visitors. This information will be used to improve our Properties.
    
    ****Analytics****
    
    We may work with third-party vendors who use the technologies described in this section to conduct website analytics to help us track and understand how visitors use our Properties. One such provider is Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies to help analyze how users use the Properties. The information generated by these cookies about your use (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Properties, compiling reports on activity for its staff, and providing other services relating to web page activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. You may refuse the use of such cookies by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser. By using the Properties and accepting cookies, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. Please refer to the currently available opt-outs for Google Analytics by visiting [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).
    
    ****Service Data****
    
    We may obtain Service Data from or on behalf of our clients and their vendors, which we process on behalf of our clients in accordance with our contracts with them.
    
    ****Third-Party Sources****
    
    From time to time, we may collect personal information about you from third party sources (including data append services such as public or social graph data, data co-ops, or social media websites if you have chosen to log in or connect your social media with our Properties) which we will use for our business or commercial purposes (for example, in order to contact you and/or to better serve you with content or promotions). However, we will only use this information where these third parties either have your consent or are otherwise legally permitted or required to disclose your personal information to us. We may also collect publicly available information from third party sources. To the extent that such information constitutes personal information, we shall use such it in accordance with this Privacy Statement or as permitted by law.
    
    When you sign into our Properties or purchase a paid subscription on our Properties using a social media log-in, you give permission to that social media company to share certain information with us. For example, if you sign in or purchase a subscription using Facebook or LinkedIn, you give permission to Facebook or LinkedIn (as applicable) to share with us your email address and certain other information in your social media profile that you have designated as public. This will be limited to your full name, age range, profile picture (if you have one) and link to your Facebook or LinkedIn profile (as applicable). If you log in or purchase a subscription using your Google account, you give Google permission to share personal information with us that you have made public in your Google profile. This will be limited to your full name, your email address (and whether your email has been validated), your age range, your profile picture (if you have one) and a link to your Google profile. If you log in or purchase a subscription using your Apple ID, you give Apple permission to share your personal information with us (however, you can choose to hide your email address and Apple will instead create a random email address so that your personal email can stay private). This email address will be linked to your account and allow you to access your subscribed content.
    
    If you log into one of our Properties using a digital wallet, you give that wallet provider permission to share certain information with us, including public data points such as your wallet address, the blockchain your wallet is on, your wallet’s transactions and transaction history, and whether the wallet holds a Forbes digital collectable.
    
    We will use the information described above to form a profile for your account, to enable you to purchase a paid subscription, and/or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Statement. You have the option to later configure your Facebook, LinkedIn, or Google settings, or Apple ID to remove permissions for Forbes to access to this information. However, this will not affect our ability to use the information that we already received when you first set up your account (or purchased a subscription) using that social media login, so long as we use it for the purposes set forth in this Privacy Statement.
    
    We may also obtain personal information of subscribers to Forbes licensees after such licensees stop conducting business under the Forbes license.
    
    #### HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
    
    We collect and use personal information for the following purposes:
    
    * _To communicate with you_, which may include:
        
        * Contacting you about and providing you and our clients with our Services;
            
        * Responding to your direct inquiries, requests, issues or feedback, and providing customer service;
            
        * Adding you to our mailing or SMS lists and sending you emails, push notifications to your digital wallets, or texts from time to time;
            
        * For users who have opted into receiving communications about Forbes’ third-party partners, sending you information about third-party partners that we think you may be interested in;
            
    * _To provide our products and services_, which may include :
        
        * Operating the Properties, and providing you with any specific services that you have requested;
            
        * Creating, maintaining, and otherwise managing your account, profile, or subscription;
            
        * Delivering content and product and service offerings relevant to your interests;
            
        * Fulfilling your orders and/or completing the transactions you have requested, processing your payments, and providing you receipts and order updates;
            
        * Providing a game leaderboard or a forum for discussion or community for Forbes honorees, asking questions, posting photos and reviews, and sharing experiences;
            
        * Considering you for and/or naming you to a Forbes list or other similar accolade (e.g., Under 30);
            
        * Organizing and managing live or virtual events;
            
        * Shipping you our print magazine;
            
        * Providing Forbes honorees with online profiles;
            
    * _For marketing, advertising, and promotional purposes_, which may include :
        
        * Marketing our goods and services or goods and services of those of our affiliates, business partners, and other third parties;
            
        * Providing you advertising for products and services that may be of interest to you;
            
        * Targeting relevant content and advertising to you on our Properties and elsewhere where we may be acting as a third party;
            
        * Providing surveys to more accurately tailor advertisements to you;
            
        * Administering sweepstakes, contests, and other similar promotions;
            
        * Conducting insights research for ourselves and our clients;
            
        * Tracking clicks on affiliated links;
            
        * Mailing you promotions or advertisements;
            
    * _For analytics, enhancement, and personalization_, which may include :
        
        * Identifying trends and making inferences about you and your interactions with us or our affiliates or our business partners;
            
        * Conducting research and analytics to improve our services and product offerings or those of our affiliates and business partners;
            
        * Understanding how you interact with our Services (including our Properties), advertisements, and communications with you to determine the appeal of our products or services, and to improve our Services and marketing campaigns;
            
        * Personalizing your experience to save you time when you visit our Properties, and to customize the marketing and advertising that we show you;
            
        * Better understanding our customers’ needs;
            
        * Providing personalized recommendations about our products and services;
            
        * Enhancing the information we may have with information from third parties;
            
    * _For security and fraud prevention_, which may include :
        
        * Helping maintain the safety, security, and integrity of our Properties, databases and other technology assets, and business;
            
        * Internal research; technological development and demonstration; and improving, upgrading, or enhancing our Properties and Services;
            
        * Detecting security incidents; protecting against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity; and prosecuting those responsible for that activity;
            
        * Investigating suspected fraud, harassment, or other violations of any law, rule, or regulation, or the policies for our Properties and Services;
            
    * _To comply with legal obligations_, which may include :
        
        * Compliance with legal or regulatory obligations, establishing or exercising our rights, and to defending against a legal claim;
            
        * Responding to law enforcement requests and as required by applicable law, court order, legal process, or governmental regulation;
            
        * Acting in connection with a bankruptcy proceeding or the sale, merger, or change of control of the Company or the division responsible for the services with which your information is associated;
            
    * _To support core business functions_, which may include :
        
        * Maintaining records related to business process management, sales, loss and fraud prevention, and to invoice and collect amounts owing to us;
            
        * Providing and maintaining the functionality of our Properties, including identifying and repairing errors or problems; and
            
    * For any additional purposes that you specifically consent to.

    We may collect information that is not personal information (“non-personal information”), including information lawfully made available from federal, state, or local government records, or aggregate or de-identified information. Because non-personal information does not personally identify you, we may collect, use, and disclose such information for any purpose permitted by law. In some instances, we may combine non-personal information with personal information. If we combine any non-personal information with personal information, the combined information will be treated by us as personal information.
    
    The Properties may offer features that allow you to post content. You should be aware that personal information which you voluntarily include and transmit online in a publicly accessible blog, forum, social network, or otherwise online may be viewed and used by others. As a general reminder, please think carefully before you decide to put anything on the Internet. For example, if you voluntarily disclose personal information in chat areas or bulletin boards (e.g., comment sections), that information could be seen and used by others, and may result in unsolicited messages from others. We are not responsible for the information you may choose to submit in these public forums. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, please contact us using the information provided in the section titled **Contacting Us**. In some cases, for legal retention purposes or technical limitations (e.g., the data may not be searchable), we may not be able to remove personal information voluntarily disclosed by you in such forums, in which case, we will notify you.
    
    Moreover, be aware that if you provide personal information that is published in our editorial content, this information will become publicly available and may be shared with third parties for any purpose permitted by law. For example, if you apply for consideration in connection with a Forbes list or similar accolade (e.g., the Under 30 list), we will process your personal information strictly in accordance with this Privacy Statement. However, if you are chosen for a Forbes list or similar accolade, and your information is published as part of our editorial content relating to such list or accolade (e.g., if you are selected for the Under 30 list), your personal information will become publicly available may be used and shared for other purposes outside the scope of this Privacy Statement.
    
    With respect to how we use Service Data, we use that information to provide Services to our clients.
    
    #### HOW WE DISCLOSE YOUR INFORMATION
    
    In addition to using your personal information ourselves, we may send your personal information and other information to other companies, affiliates, and third parties in the following instances:
    
    **Service Providers**
    
    We may share your personal information with service providers who may use your information to provide us services including, but not limited to: website hosting, data analysis, infrastructure provision, information technology services, conducting surveys and contests, customer service, email or SMS delivery services, payment processing and recouping, auditing, consulting, magazine management and shipping, event management, data security, and anti-fraud monitoring. These service providers have access to personal information that is necessary to perform their functions, and they are prohibited from using your personal information for their own commercial purposes.
    
    **Corporate Affiliates**
    
    We may share personal information with our corporate affiliates and subsidiaries, who process personal information on our behalf as our vendor, where necessary to provide a product or service that you have requested or in other circumstances with your consent or as permitted or required by law.
    
    **Business and Advertising Partners**
    
    We may share personal information with our business partners, which may include information shared for the purposes of marketing or interest-based advertising. If you provide any user information via an advertiser promotion, please be aware you are directly providing your user information to that advertiser. We may share certain event registrant user information with sponsors of our live or virtual events (e.g., attendee name, title, company name) or with Forbes licensees in circumstances where a licensee works with Forbes in the promotion or such an event, subject to applicable law. We share certain personal information of certain Forbes list nominees and honorees with our third-party partners in situations where Forbes partners with a third-party in connection with the creation of such lists. In such circumstances, the third party will be named. As mentioned above, if you are chosen for a Forbes list or similar accolade, and your information is published as part of our editorial content relating to such list or accolade, your personal information will become publicly available, and it may be used and shared for other purposes outside the scope of this Privacy Statement. For Service Data processed on behalf of our clients, like lead generation data or data collected in connection with a survey conducted for a client, we share the Service Data with our clients. We also make certain information about our print magazine subscribers available for list renters to engage in direct, physical mail marketing, but in such circumstances, no personal information is actually made available to the renter. Forbes also shares certain personal information about its subscribers and visitors with other publishers in connection with data co-ops. To learn more about how you can modify how we share your personal information, refer to the **Your Choices** section below.
    
    **Legal Compliance and to Defend Our Rights**
    
    We may disclose personal information and other information as we believe necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our Terms and Conditions; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you, or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.
    
    **Business Transfers**
    
    We may share your personal information and other information with third parties in connection with a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of the assets of the Company, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which information held by the Company about the users of our Properties and Services is among the assets transferred. In this case, we may notify you if applicable law requires.
    
    **Consent**
    
    Forbes may disclose your Personal Information to third parties with your consent or pursuant to your direction.
    
    #### DATA SECURITY
    
    We care about the protection of your personal information and use appropriate technical and organizational security measures to do so. These measures are designed to provide a level of security appropriate to the risk of processing of your personal information. Your user information is stored on Forbes servers located in the United States. We use industry standard physical, electronic, and organizational safeguards to protect your user information against loss or theft as well as unauthorized access and disclosure to protect your privacy. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by users inside and outside of the company. We also ensure that, in accordance with good industry practice, we have in place security measures to protect your personal information from interception, including in transit between our different systems and devices. This includes having in place network protection to deny attackers the ability to intercept data and the encryption of your personal information while in transit to deny attackers the ability to read data. Of course, it’s important to keep in mind that no data transmission on the Internet is guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you are concerned that your privacy may have been breached or that your interaction with us is no longer secure, please immediately notify us of the problem by contacting us as provided below.
    
    #### DATA RETENTION
    
    We will retain your user information for as long as we have an ongoing legitimate business need to use your user information (for example, to manage your active account with us or to comply with applicable tax, legal, or accounting requirements). When there is no longer such a need, we will delete it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in back-up archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible. We will also delete certain user information we may retain about you upon your request.
    
    #### INTEREST-BASED ADVERTISING
    
    **Targeted Advertising / Behavioral Advertising**
    
    We may ourselves, or with third-party vendors and advertising partners, use personal information to deliver targeted advertising to you when you visit other websites or our Properties (including emails). Cookies, clickstream data, and other similar technologies described above may be used in this process. We, along with certain advertising partners, may also convert hashed email addresses that we have of yours into pseudonymized token identifiers used for targeted advertising purposes.
    
    Targeted advertising, which is sometimes called “behavioral advertising,” or “cross-context behavioral advertising,” enables us and our vendors to know your interests in connection with the delivery of that specific ad. We believe that such advertising is helpful because you will see advertisements that are relevant to your interests. An example of how targeted advertising works is if you are searching for information on a particular product, we or our vendor or advertising partner may cause an advertisement to appear on other websites you view with information on that product. We comply with the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising as administered by the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA). If you would like to opt out of these interest-based advertisements, please follow the opt-out process described below under **Your Choices**.
    
    **Cross Device Matching**
    
    We may use information we have collected to help us, or our third-party vendors and advertising partners, determine if you have interacted with our Properties across multiple devices and to match such devices. To accomplish this, we may rely on information (including demographic, geographic, and interest-based data) from third parties such as data vendors, pursuant to their own privacy policies, or we may use information we collect in conjunction with such third-party data. Based on this data, we may then display targeted advertisements across devices that we believe are associated and may provide other services to our advertisers to better enable cross-device targeting and analysis. For further instructions on restricting our use of certain cross-device data, please see **Your Choices** below.
    
    #### YOUR CHOICES
    
    Consistent with applicable law, you may exercise the options described in this section regarding your choices with respect to your personal information and communications from us. You may also have certain additional rights available depending on your state or country of residence, as described further below.
    
    **Rights and Opt-Outs**
    
    Registered forbes.com users and Forbes community members may at any time change the information stored in their forbes.com or community member profile (such as name, password, location, country, and the topics and authors they are following) by visiting their member profile page. You may also request to delete or modify your personal account and/or any personal information you may have voluntarily submitted to us (e.g., information that you provide to register for a Forbes event) if you wish to do so, provided we are able to verify your identity in accordance with applicable law. You may also ask to opt out of direct email marketing, push notifications to your digital wallets, and SMS communications from Forbes by following the unsubscribe instructions contained in the communication you have received. For marketing emails, this is typically through an "unsubscribe" or "opt-out" link. To opt out of other forms of marketing, please contact us using the information provided in the section titled **Contacting Us** below. If you are a resident of the European Economic Area, the United Kingdom, Switzerland, California, Colorado, Connecticut, Delaware, Iowa, Minnesota, Montana, Nebraska, New Hampshire, New Jersey, Oregon, Tennessee, Texas, Utah, Virginia, or the People’s Republic of China, you may have additional rights as set forth in the subsequent sections of this Privacy Statement.
    
    **Cookies, Tracking, and Interest-Based Advertising**
    
    In certain countries and U.S. states, you can opt out or set preferences regarding cookies and other tracking technologies when a device you utilize visits our Properties, by visiting the URL [HERE](https://www.forbes.com/consent/editprivacy/?consent_preferces=true&purge=true) to access our cookie management tool. Please note that you will need to set preferences on each device you use to visit our Properties. If you would like to use your browser to stop or restrict the placement of non-Required (e.g., non-essential) cookies or flush any cookies that may already be on your computer or device, you may also refer to and adjust your web browser preferences. Further information on cookies is available at www.allaboutcookies.org. By deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies, you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our Properties or some of the functionality may be affected.
    
    The online advertising industry provides a service through which you may opt out of receiving targeted ads from certain data partners and other advertising partners that participate in self-regulatory programs. You can opt out of targeted advertising from certain providers that participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) program at [www.aboutads.info/consumers](https://www.forbes.com/privacy/english/www.aboutads.info/consumers). Other providers are members of the Network Advertising Initiative, and you can opt out of interest-based advertising by those members by visiting [http://optout.networkadvertising.org/.](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) Please note that by opting out, you may continue to see generic advertising that is not tailored to your specific interests and activities. Additionally, be advised that these industry opt-out methods will not prevent the receipt of interest-based advertising from other companies that do not participate in these programs. Cookie-based opt-outs must be performed on each device and browser that you wish to have opted out. For example, if you have opted out on your device browser, that opt-out will not be effective on your mobile device, and if you opt out on one of your devices, that opt out may not be effective on all of your devices. If you are visiting our Properties from a mobile device, the operating system of the device may offer you options regarding how the device collects and uses your information for interest-based advertising. Please visit [https://thenai.org/opt-out/mobile-opt-out/](https://thenai.org/opt-out/mobile-opt-out/) for more information. For targeted advertisements delivered through mobile apps, you can install the DAA’s AppChoices app on your device to opt out of targeted advertising by certain providers, and can also select a system-level advertising preference on your device (such as “Limit Ad Tracking” on Apple devices or “Opt-out of Interest-Based Ads” on Android devices).
    
    If you would like to opt out of the targeted adverting ecosystem run by The Trade Desk that uses pseudonymized token identifiers known as UID2 tokens created from a hashed version of your email address and/or phone number (though we don’t use phone number in connection with our participation in this ecosystem), you may do so [HERE](https://www.transparentadvertising.com/). The Trade Desk is a third-party advertising partner.
    
    **Do Not Track**
    
    While some browsers have a “do not track” (also known as DNT) feature that lets you instruct websites not to track your online activities, we do not respond to or honor DNT signals or similar mechanisms transmitted by web browsers. However, in jurisdictions where required, our Properties are designed to honor opt-out preference (aka, Global Privacy Control) signals.
    
    #### PRIVACY DISCLOSURES FOR NEVADA RESIDENTS
    
    If you are a resident of Nevada, you have the right to opt out of the sale of certain personal information to third parties who intend to license or sell that personal information. If you wish to exercise this right, [click here](https://www.forbes.com/consent/editprivacy/?consent_limit=true&purge=true) or contact us at 866-536-7262.
    
    #### CROSS-BORDER DATA TRANSFERS
    
    While the Properties and various Services are available to users globally, our primary audience is located in North America. If you submit personal information to Forbes, your personal information may be processed in a foreign country where privacy laws may be less stringent than the laws in your country. By submitting your personal information to us you agree to the transfer, storage, and processing of your personal information in a country other than your country of residence including, but not necessarily limited to, the United States. Please note that personal information transferred to the United States is subject to access by law enforcement. Where applicable, Forbes may use model clauses approved by the laws of your jurisdiction (such as Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the European Commission) or other recognized transfer mechanisms for cross-border data transfers.
    
    #### LAW ENFORCEMENT REQUESTS
    
    Forbes takes the protection of your personal information very seriously and is committed to acting as a responsible data custodian. If we become aware that any law enforcement, regulatory, judicial or governmental authority ("Authority") wishes to obtain access to, or a copy of, the personal information that we hold about you (whether on a voluntary or mandatory basis) (a "Request"), then we commit to the following: (1) we will investigate the Request before responding, to ensure that it is a valid request made under applicable law; and (2) we will only disclose personal information to the Authority in response to the Request where we are legally required to do so and in accordance with applicable lawful process. The only exception to these commitments is where we reasonably believe (in good faith) that the urgent provision of the requested personal information per the Authority's Request is necessary to prevent an imminent risk of serious harm to any individual. However, in any event, we shall never knowingly disclose personal information in a massive, disproportionate, or indiscriminate manner, which goes beyond what is necessary in a democratic society.
    
    #### CHILDREN'S PRIVACY
    
    The Properties are intended for people who are at least 18 years of age. If you are less than 18 years old, please do not send any personal information to us—including information such as your name, address, or email address. We do not knowingly collect (nor do we wish to collect) any personal information from children under the age of 18. If we learn we have collected any personal information from a child under the age of 18, we will delete that information from our database and terminate the corresponding account, if any. We encourage you to discuss the Properties with your parent or guardian.
    
    #### NOTICE OF FINANCIAL INCENTIVE
    
    We may at times offer our customers programs that provide certain perks associated with us, such as rewards and exclusive offers. We may also provide other programs, such as sweepstakes, contests, or other similar promotional campaigns (collectively, the “Programs”). When you sign up for one of these Programs, we typically ask you to provide your name and contact information (such as email address and/or telephone number). If participating in a program that requires signing up or logging in with a digital wallet, we may also require certain public data like your wallet address, the blockchain your wallet is on, your wallet’s transactions and transaction history, and whether your wallet holds a Forbes digital collectable. Because our Programs involve the collection of Personal Information, they may be considered a “financial incentive” program under California law or a “bona fide loyalty program” under Colorado law. The value of your personal information to us is exceeded by or related to the value of the free or discounted products or services, or other benefits that you obtain or that are provided as part of the applicable Program, minus the expense related to offering those products, services, and benefits to Program participants. Unless specifically stated otherwise in connection with a potential “financial incentive,” the value of the benefit Forbes may offer to you exceeds the value of the personal information you provide as a participant.
    
    You may withdraw from participating in a Program at any time by contacting us using the designated method set forth in the applicable Program rules. Please read the terms and conditions of each Program to view full details, including how to join. You may also withdraw from or opt into the Program by contacting us at the email address provided in connection with the Program. If none is provided, you may contact us as set forth above in the **Contacting Us** section.
    
    #### CHANGES TO THIS POLICY
    
    We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time in response to changing legal, technical or business developments. This Privacy Statement describes our data handling practices for the 12 months prior to the date on which it was last updated. We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions from this Privacy Statement at any time, provided that any such modifications will only be applied prospectively. We encourage you to periodically review the Site for the latest information on our privacy practices. Your continued use of the Properties or Services following the posting of any changes to this Privacy Statement means you accept such changes. If we make a material change to this Privacy Statement, we will make reasonable efforts, taking into account available technology and our relationship with you, to notify you of the change with respect to any personal information that we collect going forward. If the material change results in processing previously collected personal information in a manner that is not reasonably necessary to or compatible with the original specified purposes that we disclosed in the prior version of our Privacy Statement, we will provide a reasonable opportunity for you to withdraw consent to any further materially different processing of previously collected personal information under the changed terms.​
    
    **Note on Translated Version(s):** For your convenience, Forbes may make translated versions of this Privacy Statement available on the Site. In the event that the terms of any such translated version conflict with the terms of the English version, the terms of the English version of this Privacy Statement will apply.
    
    #### CONTACTING US
    
    If you have any other questions regarding this Privacy Statement or how to remove or modify your user information or related consents, please feel free to contact us at [privacy@forbes.com](mailto:privacy@forbes.com) or Forbes Media, Privacy Team - Customer Service, 499 Washington Blvd., Jersey City, NJ 07310. The data controller of your user information is Forbes Media LLC. You may contact our EU and UK GDPR Data Protection Officer at [gdpr.dpo@forbes.com](mailto:gdpr.dpo@forbes.com) and, if you are writing from the UK, you may contact our UK representative at Forbes Media - UK Representative, 151 Wardour Street, Offices 201-203, London, W1F 8WE. If you are writing from the EEA, you may contact our EEA GDPR Representative at [Forbes@LionheartSquared.eu](mailto:Forbes@LionheartSquared.eu) or Lionheart Squared (FAO Forbes Media), 2 Pembroke House, Upper Pembroke Street 28-32, Dublin, D02 EK84 Ireland.
    
    #### CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS
    
    The California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (“**CCPA**”), amended by the California Privacy Rights Act of 2020, provides you with specific rights regarding your Personal Information. This section describes the rights that California consumers have and explains how to exercise those rights. For the purposes of this section, “**Personal Information**” does not include: (i) information that is lawfully made available from federal, state or local government records; (ii) de-identified or aggregated data; or (iii) information excluded from the scope of the CCPA. To be clear, these rights are granted only to the extent that you are a California consumer. The rights in this section are not intended to grant you additional rights, but only your rights under the CCPA to the extent that we are considered a CCPA business with respect to the applicable Personal Information.
    
    In order to provide our Services to our clients, we may process Service Data that we receive from or on behalf of our clients. If you are a California resident, you may have certain CCPA rights pertaining to such information. Under the CCPA, when we act as a “service provider” (not as a “business” or a “third party”) over such information, we only process your information through our Services as necessary to provide our services to our clients, at our clients’ direction. If you wish to exercise any of your rights under CCPA regarding such information, please contact the relevant business that collected the information from you, who controls and determines how your information is processed.
    
    **Information We Collect; How We Collect It; How We Use It**
    
    To the extent that our collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information is addressed by a separate privacy notice, please consult the terms of that privacy notice for detailed information about our data practices, including the categories of personal information that we collect and disclose. For all other consumers, general information regarding our collection, use, and disclosure of personal information is set forth in the Privacy Statement, and more detailed information about our data practices in relation to specific categories of personal information can be found in the [**Personal Information Processing Chart**](#personal-information-processing-chart). We may disclose your Personal Information to service providers for a business purpose, or sell or share your personal information to third parties, subject to your right to opt out (see **Right to Opt Out of Selling or Sharing Your Personal Information**, below). Please note that Forbes does not “sell” any of your personal information in exchange for money. However, the term “sell” has a broader meaning under the CCPA than would ordinarily be understood in a non-legal context. The information under the [**Personal Information Processing Chart**](#personal-information-processing-chart) (or as addressed under a separate privacy notice, if applicable) describes the entities with which we may disclose your Personal Information.
    
    **Rights to Your Information**
    
    1. _Right to Know_

    As a California consumer, you have the right to request that we disclose certain information to you about our collection, use, or disclosure of your Personal Information over the past 12 months. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request (see **Exercising Your Rights**, below), and subject to certain limitations that we describe below, we will disclose such information. You have the right to request any or all of the following:
    
    * The categories of Personal Information we collected about you.
    * The categories of sources from which the Personal Information is collected.
    * Our business or commercial purpose for collecting, selling, or sharing that Personal Information.
    * The categories of third parties with whom we disclose that Personal Information.
    * The specific pieces of Personal Information we collected about you (see **Data Portability Rights** below).
    
    2. _Right to Delete_

    You have the right to request that we delete any of your Personal Information that we collected from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request (see **Exercising Your Rights**, below), we will delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your Personal Information from our records, unless an exception applies. However, we may retain Personal Information that has been de-identified or aggregated. Furthermore, we may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us or our service provider(s) in order to perform certain actions set forth under the CCPA, such as detecting security incidents and protecting against fraudulent or illegal activity.
    
    3. _Right to Data Portability_

    You have the right to request a copy of Personal Information we have collected and maintained about you. The CCPA allows you to request your information from us up to twice during a 12-month period. We will provide our response in a readily usable (and usually electronic) format.
    
    4. _Right to Correct_

    You have the right to request the correction of any Personal Information we maintain about you.
    
    5. _Right to Opt Out of Selling or Sharing Your Personal Information_

    You have the right to opt out of the sale or sharing of your Personal Information, along with the right to opt in to the sale or sharing of such information. We do not sell or share the Personal Information of consumers we actually know are less than 16 years of age, unless we receive affirmative authorization (the "right to opt-in") from either the consumer who is less than 16 (but greater than 13) years of age, or the parent or guardian of a consumer less than 13 years of age. To our knowledge, we do not sell or share the Personal Information of minors under 16 years of age. To exercise the right to opt out, you (or your authorized representative) may visit the following web page: [Do Not Sell or Share My Personal Information](https://www.forbes.com/consent/editprivacy/?consent_do_not_sell=true&purge=true). Alternatively, you may submit an opt-out request by contacting us at 866-536-7262. We will also treat opt-out preference (aka, Global Privacy Control) browser signals as valid opt out requests. You may change your mind and opt back into Personal Information sales at any time by contacting us at [privacy@forbes.com](mailto:privacy@forbes.com).
    
    6. _Right to Limit the Use of Your Sensitive Personal Information_

    You have the right to limit the use or disclosure of your sensitive personal information (“**SPI**”) if we are using your SPI beyond what is reasonable and proportionate to provide the requested goods or services. You can make a request for us to limit the use or disclosure of your SPI by visiting the following Internet Web page: “[Limit the Use of My Sensitive Personal Information](https://www.forbes.com/consent/editprivacy/?consent_limit=true&purge=true).” While we recognize opt-out preference signals (aka, Global Privacy Controls) when required to do so by law, given the specific methods by which Forbes collects your SPI in the limited circumstances it collects SPI, opt-out preference signals would be an ineffective and technologically impractical means for honoring limit the use requests. Therefore, please make your request to limit the use of your SPI using the above link.
    
    7. _Right to Non-Discrimination_

    We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights, including but not limited to, by:
    
    * Denying you goods or services.
    * Charging you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through granting discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties.
    * Providing you a different level or quality of goods or services.
    * Suggesting that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.
    
    8. _Exercising Your Rights_

    To exercise the rights described above, please contact us by using the following methods:
    
    * Calling us at 866-536-7262; or
    * Visiting our [California Resident CCPA Request Form to submit a request.](https://www.forbes.com/consent/editprivacy/?consent_limit=true&purge=true)
    
    After submitting a Delete, Correct, Portability, or Right to Know request, we will take steps to verify your identity in order for us to properly respond and confirm that it is not a fraudulent request. In order to verify your identity, we will ask, at a minimum, that you provide your name and email address so that we can match this information with the information existing in our systems. If you are a print subscriber, we may also require your mailing address to find you in our systems. When providing us this information, you represent and affirm that all information provided is true and accurate. Forbes will send you a verification email to verify that you have access to the email address you have provided. Then, as required by the CCPA, Forbes will use this information to verify your identify to a reasonable or reasonably high degree of certainty, depending on the request. Depending on how you submit the request, if we are able to verify that you have access to the email address you provided, or if we are able to match at least two pieces of personal information to the personal information that we may retain of you, we will honor your Right to Know (Categories) request and in most cases, your Right to Delete and Right to Correct requests. If we are able to verify that you have access to the email address you provided and match at least two to three pieces of personal information to the personal information that we may retain of you, we will honor your Right to Know (Data Portability / Specific Pieces of Personal Information) requests, and in situations where we determined that a reasonably high degree of certainty was more appropriate, your Right to Delete and Right to Correct requests. If we are unable to verify your identity, we will let you know that we are unable to fulfill your request.
    
    Only you, or an agent legally authorized to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable request related to your Personal Information. If you are making a request as the authorized agent of a California consumer, we may ask you also submit reliable proof that you have been authorized in writing by the consumer to act on such consumer’s behalf when permitted by law.
    
    We will make every effort to respond to your request within 45 days from when you contacted us. If you have a complex request, the CCPA allows us up to 90 days to respond. We will still contact you within 45 days from when you contacted us to let you know we need more time to respond.
    
    **CALIFORNIA “SHINE THE LIGHT”**
    
    Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83 (“Shine the Light”), California residents have the right to request in writing from businesses with whom they have an established business relationship: (a) a list of the categories of personal information, as defined under Shine the Light, such as name, email address, and mailing address, and the type of services provided to the customer that a business has disclosed to third parties (including affiliates that are separate legal entities) during the immediately preceding calendar year for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes; and (b) the names and addresses of all such third parties. To request the above information, please contact us at 866-536-7262. If you do not want your personal information shared with any third party who may use such information for direct marketing purposes, then you may opt out of such disclosures by contacting us at 866-536-7262.
    
    #### COLORADO, CONNECTICUT, DELAWARE, IOWA, MINNESOTA, MONTANA, NEBRASKA, NEW HAMPSHIRE, NEW JERSEY, OREGON, TENNESSEE, TEXAS, UTAH, VIRGINIA AND SIMILAR U.S. STATE PRIVACY RIGHTS
    
    The Colorado Privacy Act, Connecticut Data Privacy Act, Delaware Personal Data Privacy Act, Iowa Consumer Data Protection Act, Minnesota Consumer Data Privacy Act, Montana Consumer Data Privacy Act, New Hampshire Data Privacy Act, New Jersey Data Privacy Act, Nebraska Data Privacy Act, Oregon Consumer Privacy Act, Tennessee Information Protection Act, Texas Data Privacy and Security Act, Utah Consumer Privacy Act, Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act, and such other U.S. states that have comparable consumer privacy laws ("**State Privacy Laws**") provide their consumers with specific rights regarding their personal information. To the extent that you are a resident of one of these states, this section describes your rights under the State Privacy Laws and explains how you may exercise these rights. The categories of personal information we process, our purposes for processing your personal information, the categories of personal information that we share with third parties, and the categories of third parties with whom we share it are detailed above in our Privacy Statement and in the [**Personal Information Processing Chart**](#personal-information-processing-chart). To the extent that our personal information processing activities are addressed by a separate privacy notice, please consult the terms of that privacy notice for detailed information about our data practices, including the categories of personal information that we collect and disclose.
    
    **Rights to Your Information**
    
    Certain rights that you may have concerning your personal information are set forth in our Privacy Statement. State Privacy Laws provide you with the following additional rights:
    
    * **Right to know.** You have the right to know whether we process your personal information. If you are a resident of Minnesota or Oregon, you also have the rights to (i) confirm additional information about the categories of personal information we have processed about you; and (ii) obtain a list of third parties to which we have disclosed personal information of Oregon consumers. If you are a resident of Delaware, you also have the right to obtain a list of the categories of third parties to which we have disclosed personal information of Delaware consumers.
    * **Right to data portability.** Depending on your state, you either have the right to access and obtain a copy of your personal information that (i) we process about you; or (ii) you previously provided to us. We will provide this copy in a portable and, to the extent technically feasible, readily usable format that allows you to transmit the data to another business without hindrance, where the processing is carried out by automated means. You may request such personal information up to twice annually, subject to certain exceptions.
    * **Right to delete.** You have the right to delete personal information that you have provided by or that we have obtained about you. Please note that we may deny such request, in whole or in part, if the requested deletion falls under an exception to this right set forth in State Privacy Laws. Additionally, for residents of Colorado, Connecticut, and Texas, if you request deletion of your personal information and we have obtained such information from a third-party source, we may retain such data by keeping a record of the deletion request and the minimum data necessary to ensure that your personal information remains deleted from our records and that such retained data is not used for any other purpose, or we may opt you out of the processing of such personal information for any purpose except for those allowed under State Privacy Laws. Some State Privacy Laws, like those of Iowa and Utah, limit this right to only the data you have provided us.
    * **Right to opt out of selling or sharing.** You have the right to opt out of the processing of your personal information for purposes of: (i) targeted advertising; (ii) the sale of personal information; or (iii) profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning you, unless you reside in Iowa or Utah. As of the latest date of the Privacy Statement:
        * We DO process personal information for the purposes of targeted advertising;
        * We DO sell your personal information in exchange for monetary or other valuable consideration (Please note that we do not “sell” any of your personal information in exchange for money. However, the term “sell” has a broader meaning under certain State Privacy Laws than would ordinarily be understood in a non-legal context);
        * We DO NOT engage in profiling decision based on your personal information that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning you.
        * If you wish to opt out of the processing of your personal information for the purposes of targeted advertising please call us at 866-536-7262 or [click here](https://www.forbes.com/consent/editprivacy/?consent_do_not_sell=true&purge=true). For residents of Colorado, Connecticut, Minnesota, Montana, New Hampshire, New Jersey, and Texas we will also treat opt-out preference signals as valid opt-out requests to the extent required by those State Privacy Laws.
    * **Right to correct.** Unless you reside in Iowa or Utah, you have the right to correct inaccuracies in the personal information we collect from you, taking into account the nature of the personal information and the purposes for which we process it.
    * **Right to nondiscrimination.** You have the right not to receive discriminatory treatment by us for the exercise of your privacy rights. Unless permitted by State Privacy Laws, we will not:
        * Deny you goods or services.
        * Charge you different prices or rates for goods or services, including through granting discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties.
        * Provide you a different level or quality of goods or services.
        * Suggest that you may receive a different price or rate for goods or services or a different level or quality of goods or services.
    
    **How to Contact Us About Your Privacy Rights**
    
    To exercise any of your privacy rights, or if you have any questions about your privacy rights, you may contact us by:
    
    * Calling us at 866-536-7262; or
    * Visiting [Your Privacy Rights](https://www.forbes.com/consent/editprivacy/?consent_limit=true&purge=true) to submit a request.
    
    **Verification of Your Identity.** After submitting a request, we will take steps to verify your identity in order for us to properly respond and confirm that it is not a fraudulent request. In order to verify your identity, we will ask, at a minimum, that you provide your name and email address so that we can match this information with the information existing in our systems. If you are a print subscriber, we may also require your mailing address to find you in our systems. When providing us this information, you represent and affirm that all information provided is true and accurate. Forbes will send you a verification email to verify that you have access to the email address you have provided. Then, as required by the State Privacy Laws, Forbes will use this information to verify your identify to a reasonable or reasonably high degree of certainty, depending on the request. Depending on how you submit the request, if we are able to verify that you have access to the email address you provided, or if we are able to match at least two pieces of personal information to the personal information that we may retain of you, we will honor your Right to Know requests pertaining to categories, and in most cases, your Right to Delete and Right to Correct requests. If we are able to verify that you have access to the email address you provided and match at least two to three pieces of personal information to the personal information that we may retain of you, we will honor your requests that require us to provide you with your personal information, like Data Portability and certain Right to Know requests, and in situations where we determined that a reasonably high degree of certainty was more appropriate, your Right to Delete and Right to Correct requests. If we are unable to verify your identity, we will let you know that we are unable to fulfill your request.
    
    Only you—or for Colorado, Connecticut, Delaware, Nebraska, Montana, New Hampshire, New Jersey, Oregon, Minnesota, or Texas consumers making an opt-out request, an agent legally authorized to act on your behalf—may make a verifiable request related to your personal information. If you are making an opt-out request as the authorized agent of a consumer in the above mentioned states, we may ask you to also submit reliable proof that you have been authorized in writing by the consumer to act on such consumer’s behalf to the extent permitted by law. If you are making a request as the parent or legal guardian of a known child regarding the processing of that child’s personal information, we may ask you to submit reliable proof of your identity.
    
    **Our Response Time to Your Request**
    
    We will make every effort to respond to your request within 45 days from when you contacted us. If you have a complex request, State Privacy Laws allow us an additional 45 days to respond. We will still contact you within 45 days from when you contacted us to let you know we need more time to respond and the reason for the extension.
    
    **Your Right to Appeal**
    
    If we decline to take action regarding a request that you have submitted, we will inform you of our reason for declining to take action and, unless you are a Utah resident, provide instructions for how to appeal the decision. In the event that we do not respond to a request that you make pursuant to one of the privacy rights set forth in this section, unless you are a Utah resident, you have the right to appeal our refusal to take action within a reasonable period of time after you receive our decision. Within 60 days (45 for residents of Colorado and Minnesota) of our receipt of an appeal, we will inform you in writing of any action taken or not taken in response to the appeal, including a written explanation of the reasons for the decisions. If the appeal is denied, we will also provide you with an online mechanism, if available, or other method through which you may contact your state attorney general’s office to submit a complaint.
    
    #### EUROPEAN PRIVACY RIGHTS
    
    IF YOU ARE SITUATED IN THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA, SWITZERLAND, OR THE UNITED KINGDOM, THIS SECTION APPLIES TO OUR COLLECTION, USE, AND DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND ADDITIONAL RIGHTS YOU HAVE UNDER APPLICABLE LAW.
    
    **Legal Basis**
    
    We will only use your personal data, as that term is defined under the General Data Protection Regulation (“**GDPR**”), when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:
    
    * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
    * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
    * Where you have consented to a certain use of your personal data.
    * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
    
    To the extent permitted under applicable laws, we will also process, transfer, disclose, and preserve personal data when we have a good faith belief that doing so is necessary.
    
    **Data Controller**
    
    Forbes is the data controller of all personal data collected through our Properties or Services (with the exception of Service Data, for which Forbes is a data processor). To contact us, please see the section above titled **Contacting Us**. If you are situated in the EEA, Switzerland, or the UK and have any complaints regarding our privacy practices, you have the right to make a complaint at any time to your local supervisory authority. We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach your supervisory authority, so please contact us in the first instance. If you have a complaint, please contact our privacy manager here: [privacy@forbes.com](mailto:privacy@forbes.com).
    
    **Provision of personal data and failure to provide personal data**
    
    Where we need to collect personal data by law or under the terms of a contract we have with you, and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with our services). In this case, we may not be able to provide certain services to you.
    
    **Collection of personal data from third-party sources**
    
    We may obtain personal data and other information about you from public sources and through our third-party partners who help us provide our products and services to you.
    
    **Withdrawing your consent**
    
    If we are relying on your consent to process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at [privacy@forbes.com](mailto:privacy@forbes.com). You must, however, specify what processing activity or activities you are withdrawing your consent from.
    
    **Data Transfer**
    
    We may transfer personal data from the EEA, Switzerland, and the UK to the USA and other countries, some of which have not been determined by the European Commission or the UK to have an adequate level of data protection. Where we transfer personal data protected under EEA, Swiss, and UK data protection law to countries not deemed adequate, we take appropriate safeguards to ensure that your personal data will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Statement and applicable laws. The safeguards we use include specific contracts (such as the UK and EEA Standard Contractual Clauses) approved by the European Commission or the UK Secretary of State. For more information about how we transfer your data, please contact us at [privacy@forbes.com](mailto:privacy@forbes.com).
    
    Forbes participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (the “**EU-U.S. DPF**”), the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF (the “**UK Extension**”), and the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (the “**Swiss-U.S. DPF**”), as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce. Forbes is committed to applying the EU-U.S. DPF's applicable Principles to personal data we receive from the European Union in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF and to personal data we receive from the United Kingdom (and Gibraltar) in reliance on the UK Extension. Likewise, Forbes is committed to applying the Swiss-U.S. DPF's applicable Principles to personal data we receive from Switzerland in reliance on the Swiss-U.S. DPF. For clarity, Forbes will only rely on the UK Extension and the Swiss-U.S. DPF as transfer mechanisms under the applicable UK and Swiss data protection laws, once respectively (i) the adequacy regulations implementing the data bridge for the UK Extension enter into force; and (ii) the Swiss Federal Administration's recognition of adequacy of the Swiss-U.S. DPF enters into force. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the EU-U.S. DPF and/or the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, the Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Data Privacy Framework (“DPF”) program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/).
    
    Forbes is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each DPF, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Forbes complies with the DPF Principles for all onward transfers of personal data we receive from the European Union, the UK, Gibraltar, and Switzerland in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF Principles, the UK Extension and/or the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, including the onward transfer liability provisions. In particular, where we have received your personal information in the United States in reliance upon the EU-U.S. DPF Principles, the UK Extension and/or the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles and we subsequently transfer that information to a third party acting as an agent, and such third party agent processes your personal information in a manner inconsistent with those Principles, we will remain responsible unless we can prove we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.
    
    With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the DPFs, Forbes is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Forbes may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
    
    Forbes commits to refer unresolved complaints concerning our handling of personal data received in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF to TRUSTe, an alternative dispute resolution provider based in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your DPF Principles-related complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your DPF Principles-related complaint to your satisfaction, please visit [https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request) for more information or to file a complaint. These dispute resolution services are provided at no cost to you.
    
    Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Data Privacy Framework website at, [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/article/How-to-Submit-a-Complaint-Relating-to-a-Participating-Organization-s-Compliance-with-the-DPF-Principles-dpf](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/s/article/How-to-Submit-a-Complaint-Relating-to-a-Participating-Organization-s-Compliance-with-the-DPF-Principles-dpf), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.
    
    **Use of your personal data for marketing purposes**
    
    We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising:
    
    * **Promotional offers from us:** We may use your personal data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing). You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or used our services and, in each case, you have consented to our use of your personal data for marketing purposes.
    
    **Data Subject Rights**
    
    If you are situated in the European Union, Switzerland, or the UK, under the GDPR, as a data subject, you have the right to:
    
    * **Request access to your personal data** (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
    * **Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you.** This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
    * **Request erasure of your personal data.** This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully, or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
    * **Object to processing of your personal data** where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
    * **Request restriction of processing of your personal data.** This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise, or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
    * **Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party.** We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
    * **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
    
    To exercise your rights under the GDPR, [click here](https://www.forbes.com/consent/editprivacy/?consent_limit=true&purge=true) or contact us by using the information in the **Contacting Us** section in the Privacy Statement. Please note that in order for you to assert these rights, we may need to verify your identity to confirm your right to access your personal data. This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. In order to verify your identity, we may need to gather more personal data from you than we currently have.
    
    #### PEOPLE’S REPUBLIC OF CHINA PRIVACY RIGHTS
    
    If you are a resident of the People’s Republic of China (“PRC”), you have the right to access, correct, and delete your personal information under the Personal Information Protection Law (“PIPL”). You can also request to restrict or object to certain processing of your personal information, and request a copy of your personal information. If you are a close relative of a person in the PRC who is now deceased, you can request to access, correct, and delete their personal information. Finally, you have the right to request additional information about the third parties that Forbes shares your personal information with. To exercise these rights under the PIPL, [click here](https://www.forbes.com/consent/editprivacy/?consent_limit=true&purge=true) or contact us at [privacy@forbes.com](mailto:privacy@forbes.com). We will need to verify your identify according to applicable law, which may require that we ask you for additional information to confirm your identity. We will do our best to respond to your request within 30 days and, in any event, we will respond within the timeframe required by applicable law. You can modify your cookie preferences by following the procedures outlined in the **Your Choices** section of the Privacy Statement above. If you cannot understand this Privacy Statement, you are entitled to request explanations of how we process your personal information. If you have any questions, please contact us at privacy@forbes.com. (如果您无法理解本隐私政策并希望获得更多信息，请发送电子邮件至 [privacy@forbes.com](mailto:privacy@forbes.com).)
    
    #### PERSONAL INFORMATION PROCESSING CHART
    
    In the past 12 months, we have collected the following categories of personal information from the sources described in the section of the Privacy Policy above titled **How We Collect Your Personal Information**. The chart below describes our business or commercial purposes for collecting and disclosing these categories personal information, the parties we have disclosed such information to, and whether we have sold or shared (or otherwise disclosed for targeted advertising) each category of personal information. Depending on your level of interaction with us, we may not have collected your personal information from all of the categories listed below. The categories of personal information described below are retained and stored for as long as is necessary to effectuate the business and commercial purposes for which they have been collected, and otherwise as described in the section of the Privacy Policy above titled **Data Retention**. Please note that Forbes does not “sell” any of your personal information in exchange for money. However, the term “sell” has a broader meaning under applicable privacy laws than would ordinarily be understood in a non-legal context.
    
    |     |     |     |     |     |     |
    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |Personal Information Disclosure Table
    | Category | Examples | Business or Commercial Purposes for Collecting Personal Information (Forbes may or may not use each data type in the "Examples" column for each purpose listed out) | Disclosed in the Prior Twelve (12) Months for the Following Business Purposes | “Sold” or “Shared” in the Prior Twelve (12) Months for the Following Purposes | Categories of Third Parties With Whom We Disclose, Sell, or Share Personal Information |
    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
    | Personal identifiers | A real name, postal address, online identifier, Internet Protocol address, email address, account name | **Business Purposes:** To communicate with you; to provide products and services, and to maintain their quality and safety; to identify and repair errors; to process and fulfill orders and transactions; for surveys, sweepstakes, and contests; marketing and promotions; to enable commenting and communities; for internal reporting and service optimization; to serve you content recommendations and advertising; auditing related to counting ad impressions and unique visitors; marketing and promotions; to consider you for a Forbes list or similar accolade; for lead generation services performed on behalf of our clients; to enhance the information we may have on you; security and fraud prevention; to enable exercise of privacy rights; digital wallet information to allow you to log into Forbes digital properties, monitor whether your wallet contains a Forbes digital collectable, and provide other benefits related to your use of a digital wallet; to verify customer information; to provide customer service  <br>  <br>**Commercial Purposes:** to provide marketing and advertising, including targeted advertising; sharing event registrant information with event sponsors | For the listed Business Purposes to be performed on our behalf | For the listed Commercial Purposes | Forbes affiliates; service providers; event sponsors; business and advertising partners, |
    | Personal information covered by the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e))<br><br>(Some personal information in this category may overlap with other categories) | A name, physical characteristics or description, address, telephone number, credit card number, debit card number | **Business Purposes:** To communicate with you; to provide products and services, and to maintain their quality and safety; to process and fulfill orders and transactions; for surveys, sweepstakes, and contests; marketing and promotions; to enable commenting and communities; for internal reporting and service optimization; to serve you content recommendations and advertising; to consider you for a Forbes list or similar accolade; for lead generation services performed on behalf of our clients; to enhance the information we may have on you; security and fraud prevention; to enable exercise of privacy rights; to verify customer information; to provide customer service  <br>  <br>**Commercial Purposes:** sharing event registrant information with event sponsors (e.g., name, work address, work phone) | For the listed Business Purposes to be performed on our behalf | For name, work address and phone information, only for the listed Commercial Purposes | Forbes affiliates; service providers; event sponsors; business and advertising partners |
    | Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law. | Age, race, national origin, citizenship, marital or familial status, sex, gender, veteran status, and other similar information | **Business Purposes:** To provide you with products and services, and to maintain their quality and safety; marketing and promotions; for internal reporting and service optimization; to serve you content recommendations and advertising (e.g., based on age or gender); to consider you for a Forbes list or similar accolade; to provide customer service  <br>  <br>**Commercial Purposes:** to provide marketing and advertising, including targeted advertising (e.g., based on age or gender); sharing event registrant information with event sponsors (e.g., age or gender) | For the listed Business Purposes to be performed on our behalf | For age and gender information, only the listed Commercial Purposes | Forbes affiliates; service providers; event sponsors; business and advertising partners |
    | Commercial information | Records of products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies | **Business Purposes:** To communicate with you; to provide products and services, and to maintain their quality and safety; marketing and promotions; to process and fulfill orders and transactions; for internal reporting and service optimization; to serve you content recommendations and targeted advertising; digital wallet information to allow you to log into Forbes digital properties, monitor whether your wallet contains a Forbes digital collectable, and provide other benefits related to your digital wallet; to provide customer service; to verify customer information  <br>  <br>**Commercial Purposes:** to provide marketing and advertising, including targeted advertising | For the listed Business Purposes to be performed on our behalf | For the listed Commercial Purposes | Forbes affiliates; service providers; business and advertising partners |
    | Internet or other similar network activity | browsing history, search history, information on a consumer's interaction with a website, app, or ad | **Business Purposes:** To communicate with you; to provide you with products and services, and to maintain their quality and safety; to identify and repair errors; for surveys, sweepstakes, and contests; marketing and promotions; for internal reporting and service optimization; to serve you content recommendations and advertising; auditing related to counting ad impressions and unique visitors; security and fraud prevention; to feature recommended products and services accompanied by affiliate links where we may earn a commission if you click through the links; to enable exercise of privacy rights  <br>  <br>**Commercial Purposes:** to provide marketing and advertising, including targeted advertising; to feature recommended products and services accompanied by affiliate links where we may earn a commission if you click through the links | For the listed Business Purposes to be performed on our behalf | For the listed Commercial Purposes | Forbes affiliates; service providers; business and advertising partners |
    | Geolocation data | Location tracking information | **Business Purposes:** To communicate with you; to provide you with products and services, and to maintain their quality and safety; for internal reporting and service optimization; to serve you content recommendations and advertising; auditing related to counting ad impressions and unique visitors; marketing and promotions; security and fraud prevention; to feature recommended products and services accompanied by affiliate links where we may earn a commission if you click through the links; to enable exercise of privacy rights  <br>  <br>**Commercial Purposes:** to provide marketing and advertising, including targeted advertising; to feature recommended products and services accompanied by affiliate links where we may earn a commission if you click through the links | For the listed Business Purposes to be performed on our behalf | For the listed Commercial Purposes | Forbes affiliates; service providers; business and advertising partners |
    | Sensory data | Audio, visual, or similar information | **Business Purposes:** To provide you with products and services, and to maintain their quality and safety; in relation to your user profile, your Forbes list or similar accolade profile, or when you post content; customer service call recordings; when taking photographs or videos of and at live Forbes events | For the listed Business Purposes to be performed on our behalf | N/A | Forbes affiliates; service providers |
    | Professional or employment-related information | Education, Employer, employment history, and other employment-related information | **Business Purposes:** To communicate with you; to provide you with products and services, and to maintain their quality and safety; for surveys, sweepstakes, and contests; marketing and promotions; for internal reporting and service optimization; to serve you content recommendations and advertising; auditing related to counting ad impressions and unique visitors; to consider you for a Forbes list or similar accolade; for lead generation services performed on behalf of our clients; to provide customer service; to verify customer information; to process and fulfill orders and transactions  <br>  <br>**Commercial Purposes:** to provide marketing and advertising, including targeted advertising; sharing event registrant information with event sponsors | For the listed Business Purposes to be performed on our behalf | For the listed Commercial Purposes | Forbes affiliates; service providers; event sponsors; business and advertising partners |
    | Inferences drawn from other personal information for profiling purposes | Used to create a profile reflecting a person's preferences, characteristics, and behavior | **Business Purposes:** To communicate with you; to provide you products and services, and to maintain their quality and safety; for internal reporting and service optimization; to identify and repair errors; to serve you content recommendations and advertising; auditing related to counting ad impressions and unique visitors; for surveys; marketing and promotions; to provide customer service  <br>  <br>**Commercial Purposes:** to provide marketing and advertising, including targeted advertising | For the listed Business Purposes to be performed on our behalf | For the listed Commercial Purposes | Forbes affiliates; service providers; business and advertising partners |
    | Sensitive personal information | Racial or ethnic origin; payment card information | **Business Purposes:** We collect your payment card information to fulfill, process and manage transactions, services, and subscriptions; provide customer service; to verify identities when required and permissible; with your consent, we collect racial or ethnic origin information from event registrants to track, report on, and improve upon diversity; in connection with considering you for a Forbes list or similar accolade, you may provide Forbes with nationality or immigration status information; in connection with a sweepstakes you have won, we may collect your social security number if you are required to complete a W-9 (US only); | For the listed Business Purposes to be performed on our behalf | N/A | Forbes affiliates; service providers |
